我猜想我的声音早已没机会被你听见
I guess I'm losing hope that you can hear me.
但机会永远存在  不是吗
But there's always that chance, isn't there?
那渺茫的机会
That slim chance.
现在而言  一切机会都是渺茫的
It's all about slim chances now.
我试着把每件事做对
I tried to do everything right.
确保人们的安全
Keep people safe.
我尽力了  摩根
I tried, Morgan.
我尽力了
I tried.
我们的团体变得更小了
Our group's smaller now.
我们又失去了一员  就在前天
We lost another, day before last.
那是她的选择
It was her choice.
我并不能去责怪她
I won't say I blame her,
但她失去了生存的信念
But she lost faith.
疾控中心那是条死路
The C.D.C. was a dead end.
我在那里遇见了一个男人
I met a man there,
一位科学家
A scientist.
他对我说了一些事
He told me something.
他对我说...
He told me...
那已经无关紧要了
It doesn't matter.
重点是  我们要前进了
What matters is we're moving on.
亚特兰大这边沦陷了
Atlanta's done.
我们要去本宁堡军事基地那边
We're gonna try for fort benning.
我们要面对一个漫长艰险的旅途
We're facing a long hard journey,
也许比我想象中还要来的艰难
maybe even harder than I can imagine.
但它并不会比我们至今经历的困难
But it can't be harder than our journey's been so far.
不是吗
Can it?
125里路...
125 miles...
还有这么长的路要赶
That's what lies ahead.
我试着不丧失信念
And I'm trying hard not to lose faith.
我也不能丧失  否则  其他的人...
I can't. If I do, the others...
我的家庭  我的老婆...
My family, my wife...
我的儿子
My son.
我们现在剩下的人不多了
There's just a few of us now.
所以我们要万众一心
So we've got to stick together,
互相鼓励
fight for each other,
把我们的性命互相托付
be willing to lay down our lives for each other
如果情势所迫的话
if it comes to that.
小伙儿  出发吧
Son, let's saddle up.
这是我们唯一的机会
It's the only chance we've got.
摩根  你在外边小心点儿
Be careful out there, Morgan.
希望你和杜安父子平安
I hope you and Duane are okay.
远离马路
Stay off the road.
别停下来
Keep moving.
眼观六路
Keep your eyes open.
我也不知该说啥
I don't know, just--
总之小心点儿
Just be safe.
本宁堡:乔治亚州西部城镇
也许我们能在本宁堡再相会
Maybe we'll see you in Fort Benning someday.
瑞克  完毕
Rick signing off.
翻译 小勒
翻译 威廉
翻译 公主
翻译 米苏
翻译 ksana
翻译 悟空
翻译 佩顿
翻译 Amalia
翻译 阿曦
翻译 句号
翻译 Wdjmhs
翻译 lemony
时间轴 加森 华哥 三水 何何
校对 奶昔 小勒  lemony
后期制作 、青衣
走
肉
行尸
‘第二季 第一集’
总监：lemony
刚想起和卡尔去大峡谷的那次旅行
Just thinking about our trip to the Grand Canyon with Carl.
我不记得这事儿了
I don't remember that.
不  你记不得  你那时只是个婴儿
No, you wouldn't. You were just a baby.
况且  我们其实连沃斯堡都还没到
Besides, we never made it past Fort Worth.
沃斯堡:德克萨斯州东北部城市
还真没  你那时病了
No, you got sick.
我从不知道婴儿能吐得这么厉害
I never knew a baby could throw up so much.
真恶心
Ick.
是啊  很恶心
Yeah, ick.
德州的医生说你能活下来
The doctor in Texas said you'd live.
所以我们就掉头回家了
Then we turned around and drove home.
真没劲儿
That sucks.
不  那次旅行很棒
No, it was a good trip.
最棒的一次
The best.
我们能去看看吗  去大峡谷
Can we go see it? The Grand Canyon?
我想去
I'd like to.
我也想去
I would too.
我们能去吗
Can we go?
去的话一定会带上你和你妈妈的
We'd never go without you and your mom.
我保证
That's a promise.
看起来很复杂啊
Looks complicated.
诀窍在于  怎么拆的
The trick is getting all these pieces
就怎么装回去
back together the same way.
我能把你的也清洗一下
I could clean yours,
给你示范一下
show you how.
真不错
Oh yeah.
这是把好枪
It's a sweet piece.
它是份礼物
It was a gift.
我爸爸送的
From my father.
他在我和艾米出门旅行前交给我的
He gave it to me just before amy and I took off on our road trip.
他说  两个姑娘出门在外
He said two girls on their own
要能够保护自己
should be able to defend themselves.
你爸爸是个聪明人
Smart man, your father.
你看这枪
Look, it's a--
这枪弹容有限
It's a limited capacity.
瞧  只能装七发子弹
See? Only holds seven rounds.
天呐
Oh Jeez.
这下完了
Aw no.
有路能过去吗
See a way through?
也许我们该往回走
Uh, maybe we should just go back.
-那边有跨州的辅路  -咱们油不够
- There's an interstate bypass.  - We can't spare the fuel.
天呐
Jeez.
我们能从这儿过去吗
Can we get through here?
我早就说过了  不是吗
I said it. Didn't I say it?
说了几千遍了  没水散热终究是不行的
A thousand times. Dead in the water.
有问题吗  戴尔
Problem, Dale?
没什么  不过是被困在在荒郊野外
Just a small matter of being stuck in the middle of nowhere
没有希望而已
with no hope of--
好吧  我说错了
Okay, that was dumb.
如果在这儿都找不到软胶管的话...
If you can't find a radiator hose here...
这里能找到一大堆东西呢
There's a whole bunch of stuff we can find.
我可以用水管多抽出点燃料以便启动
I can siphon more fuel from these cars for a start.
-也许能还能找到水  -或者食物
- Maybe some water. - Or food.
这是个坟场
This is a graveyard.
我真不知道自己作何感受
I don't know how I feel about this.
好了好了  开始吧
All right, all right, here we go.
大家赶紧  看看周围
Come on, y'all. Just look around,
收集能利用的一切东西
gather what you can.
孩子们  别去看它
Kids, don't look.
-要哪个  -平头螺丝刀
- Which one? - The flathead.
散热片软管的夹片从来都用平头的
Radiator hose clamp is always a flathead.
给  你来弄
Here, you do it.
学点技术
Learn something.
爱德从不让我穿这样漂亮的衣服
Ed never let me wear nice things like this.
我们会需要这些衣服的
We're gonna need clothes.
卡尔
Hey, Carl.
别离开我的视线  好吗
Always within my sight, okay?
你也是  索菲亚
You too, Sophia.
一切安好
It's all good.
好吧
Okay.
我能行的
All right.
格伦
Glenn.
我们缺水吗
Were we short on water?
给我留点
Save me some!
这简直像在接受洗礼  伙计
It's like being baptized, man.
我的上帝
Oh christ.
洛莉  躲到车底下
Lori, under the cars.
卡尔  索菲亚  赶快趴下
Carl, Sophia, get down now.
卡尔和索菲亚  索菲亚
Carl and Sophia. Sophia.
嘘  到下面来
Shh shh. Get under.
怎么回事
What?
小声点
Shh.
洛莉
Lori.
有两个行尸在追我的孩子
There's two walkers are after my baby.
嘘  安静
Shh shh!
-你还好吗  没事吧  -开枪打它们
- Are you all right? Are you okay? - Shoot them!
不  不行
No. No!
那些在马路上的行尸会听见的
Those walkers on the road would hear it.
那时就不止两个了  会有几百个过来
Then it wouldn't be just two, it'd be hundreds.
来我这  快点
Come here. Come on.
好了  在这等一下
All right, just hold here.
你别动  等着
You stay there. Wait.
快来
Come on.
索菲亚  你要完全按照我说的去做
Sophia, you have to do exactly as I say.
躲到那儿  越里面越好
Hide in there. Squeeze in tight.
-我去把它们引开  -不不  别丢下我
- I'll draw them away from you. - No no, don't leave me.
听我说  听我说
Listen listen listen listen.
它们不会气喘吁吁  而我会
They don't get winded. I do.
每次我只能解决其中的一个
I can only deal with them one at a time.
所以我就没法保护你
I wouldn't be able to protect you.
只有这样我们才能都活下来  明白吗
This is how we both survive. You understand?
好吗  去  去躲起来
Okay? Go go go go.
要是我没能回来  你就跑回公路去
If I don't make it back, run back to the highway,
从我们来的路直接跑回去找其他人
back to the others straight the way we came.
保证阳光落在你的左肩上
Keep the sun on your left shoulder.
来啊
Come on!
你们这些丑陋的狗崽子  来啊
You ugly son of a bitch. Come on!
来啊
Come on!
过来
快来啊
Come on!
你确定是这里吗
You sure this is the spot?
我就将她留在这里的
I left her right here.
我将行尸们沿着小河向上游引走了
I drew the walkers way off in that direction up the creek.
也没有船桨使唤  估计也就是这地方了
Without a paddle-- seems where we've landed.
我回来的时候她已经走了
She was gone by the time I got back here.
我以为她刚刚离开去找其他人了
I figured she just took off and ran back to the group.
我告诉她沿着那条路
I told her go that way
并且要保证阳光落在左肩上
and keep the sun on her left shoulder.
小短腿  站那边去
Hey, short round, why don't you step off to one side?
你这样会毁掉踪迹的
You're mucking up the trail.
希望她分得清左右
Assuming she knows her left from her right.
肖恩  她明白我说的话
Shane, she understood me fine.
她又累又害怕  伙计
Kid's tired and scared, man.
她刚刚从两个行尸身边死里逃生
She had her a close call with two walkers.
你说的话有多少能起作用很值得怀疑
Got to wonder how much of what you said stuck.
这里有清晰的脚印
Got clear prints right here.
她按你说的做了  向公路边走去
She did like you said, headed back to the highway.
我们分散开沿来路返回
Let's spread out, make our way back.
她不可能走太远的
She couldn't have gone far.
我们会找到她的
Hey, we gonna find her.
她一定是藏在某个灌树丛中
She'll be tuckered out hiding in a bush somewhere.
到这之前她都没问题
She was doing just fine till right here.
她就一直走着
All she had to do was keep going.
但从这里她就向那边偏离了
She veered off that way.
为什么要这么做
Why would she do that?
也许是看到什么东西  受到惊吓
Maybe she saw something that spooked her,
被迫向那边跑去
made her run off.
行尸吗
A walker?
看不到其他脚印啊
I don't see any other footprints.
只有她的
Just hers.
现在怎么办  我们所有人再继续找下去吗
So what do we do? All of us press on?
不行  最好是你和格伦回到公路那边
No, better if you and Glenn get back up to the highway.
否则其他人会惊慌失措的
People are gonna start panicking.
告诉他们我们正在尽力追踪她的踪迹
Let them know we're on her trail doing everything we can.
但是最重要的是  让大家保持冷静
But most of all, keep everybody calm.
我会让他们继续在车辆之中搜寻宝物
I'll keep 'em busy scavenging cars.
想些其他的事情  我会让他们保持忙碌的
Think up a few other chores. I'll keep 'em occupied.
走吧
Come on.
我们为什么不一起出去找
Why aren't we all out there looking?
为什么要把车子挪开
Why are we moving cars?
我们必须清理出足够的空间
We have to clear enough room so I can get the R.V.
这样房车修好之后才能掉头
turned around as soon as it's running.
既然有了燃料  我们可以原路返回
Now that we have fuel we can double back
往格伦在地图上标记的那个支路上开
to a bypass that Glenn flagged on the map.
比起清理这些破烂玩意
Going back's going to be
原路返回要容易的多
easier than trying to get through this mess.
在我女儿回来之前  我们哪也不能去
We're not going anywhere till my daughter gets back.
那还用说
Hey, that goes without saying.
瑞克和达里尔已经去找了不是吗
Rick and daryl, they're on it, okay?
-只是时间问题  -越快越好
- Just a matter of time. - Can't be soon enough for me.
我仍然对路过我们的那群畜生心有余悸
I'm still freaked out from that herd that passed us by,
-不管你们叫它什么  -那是什么情况
- or whatever you'd call it. - Yeah, what was that?
像游街一样走过去
All of them just marching along like that.
畜生  还真是那么回事
A herd. That sounds about right.
我们之前也遇到过
We've seen it.
跟那晚帐篷遭到的攻击一样
It's like the night camp got attacked.
一群行尸而已  没上次那么多罢了
Some wadering pack, only fewer.
好了
Okay.
干活吧  我们还有很多事要做
Come on, people. We still got a lot to do.
别闲着  来吧
Let's stay on it. Let's go, come on.
足迹消失了
Tracks are gone.
没有  只是变模糊了
No, they're faint,
并没有消失
But they ain't gone.
她来过这
She came through here.
你怎么知道的
How can you tell?
除了泥土和杂草我什么也看不到
I don't see anything. Dirt, grass.
你想让我给你上堂追踪课
You want a lesson in tracking
还是想赶紧找到那个女孩离开这
or you want to find that girl and get our ass off that interstate?
- 肖恩  - 卡尔  怎么了
- Shane. - Carl, what happened?
妈  我找到一个很酷的东西
Mon, I found something cool.
肖恩  你看
Shane, check it out.
是个武器匣
It's an arsenal.
确实很酷  送到戴尔那去吧
That's cool, bud. Go give 'em to Dale.
你看这个
Check this one out.
哇  是把斧头
Whoa, it's a hatchet.
小心点  别碰这些东西
be careful. Don't play with those.
真锋利啊
They're really sharp.
-你没听见我说的话吗  -我能留一个吗
- What did I just say? - Can I keep one?
-你疯了吗  -别这样
- Are you crazy? - No way.
肖恩  肖恩  让她给我留一个
Shane. Shane, tell her to let me keep one.
小兄弟  快送到戴尔那去  快
Hey, man, go give them all to dale now. Go.
-你那是什么态度  -什么
- What was that? - What was what?
你刚刚把他支走的口气
The way you blew him off just now.
你让他很难堪
You crushed him.
真不敢相信  你竟然对我这么冷淡
I don't believe you. You're giving me the cold shoulder?
这不是正和你意吗
Isn't that what you want?
你不是让我滚远点吗  让我离你们远点吗
Aren't you the one who said stay the hell away from him and you?
你忘记在疾控中心发生的事了吗
You forget what happened at the C.D.C.?
忘记你在娱乐室干的蠢事了吗
Your little meltdown in the rec room slip your mind?
-你打算...  -我打算干嘛
- When you tried-- - When I tried to what?
你认为我想干嘛
What do you think that was?
我很清楚你当时想干嘛
I think it is pretty plain what that was.
那是个错误  我承认
A mistake. One that I admit to.
我做过很多错事  洛莉
I have a few mistakes under my belt, Lori.
你也一样
So do you.
我不否认
No debate there.
可是肖恩  我们不能再这样下去了
But Shane, we need to stop this.
不然你觉得我准备新车干嘛
Why do you think I'm prepping my new ride?
我要走了
I'm leaving.
走
Leaving?
再也不回来了
As in gone for good.
一找到机会就悄悄离开
Gonna quietly slip away first chance I get.
"紧急预警系统已启动"
"The emergency alert system has been activated."
"民防办公室发布以下信息"
"The Office of Civil Defense has issued the following message:"
"立即终止常规广播"
"Normal broadcasting will cease immediately."
-"现在是非常时刻"  -这是当地信号吗
- "This is a civil emergency." - Is that a local signal?
信号源肯定在50英里之内
It's got to be within 50 miles of here.
"不惜一切代价避免感染  保持镇定"
"Avoid anyone infected at all costs. Remain calm."
"救援马上就到"
"Help is on the way."
"紧急预警系统已启动"
"The emergency alert system has been activated."
"民防办公室..."
"The Office of Civil Defense..."
去他妈的
Asshole.
好了  继续干活吧
Okay, let's get back to work.
索菲亚
Sophia!
你在找什么
What are you looking for?
指甲里有皮肤残屑
Skin under the fingernails.
它刚用过餐
It fed recently.
牙缝里还有肉
There's flesh caught in its teeth.
那是什么肉啊
Yeah, what kind of flesh?
只有一种办法能够确定
Only one way to know for sure.
我来吧
Here, I'll do it.
你这辈子开过几次膛啊
How many kills you skin and gut in your life?
不管怎样  我这把更锋利
Anyway, mine is sharper.
接下来就比较恶心了
Now comes the bad part.
看来这王八蛋刚吃了顿大餐
Yeah, hoss had a big meal not long ago.
我能摸到
I feel it in there.
-胃给你  -我来吧
- here's the gut bag. - I got this.
这恶心的家伙午餐吃的是土拨鼠
This gross bastard had himself a woodchuck for lunch.
至少搞清楚了
At least we know.
很晚了  天要黑了
It's late. Gonna be dark soon.
他们会找到她的
They'll find her.
我的手枪在哪儿
Where's my gun?
你没有权力拿走它
You have no right to take it.
你现在也用不着  不是吗
You don't need that just now, do you?
那是父亲给我的  它是我的
My father gave it to me. It's mine.
我先替你保管
I can hold onto it for you.
还是还给我吧
Or you can give it back to me.
怎么了
Everything cool?
没事  我只想要回我的枪
No, I want my gun back.
我觉得那不是个好主意
I don't think it's a good idea right now.
为什么
Why not?
我不愿意
I'm not comfortable with it.
事实是
The truth is,
营地里的流动枪支越少越好
less guns we have floating around camp the better.
你自己的武器上交了吗
You turning over your weapon?
没
No.
但我受过训练
But I'm trained in its use.
你们都需要接受枪支训练
That's what the rest of y'all need is proper training.
在那之前
But until that time I think
我觉得最好先让戴尔保管
it's best if Dale keeps them all accounted for.
到底怎么回事
Mind telling me what that's about?
天哪  他们回来了
Oh god, they're back.
你们没找到她吗
You didn't find her?
她的足迹中途消失了
Her trail went cold.
我们明天一早再去找
We'll pick it up again at first light.
你们不能把我女儿丢在荒郊野岭
You can't leave my daughter out there on her own
让她独自在丛林里过夜
to spend the night alone in the woods.
天黑了没法找
Out in the dark's no good.
容易伤着自己人
We'd just be tripping over ourselves.
会有更多人走失的
More people get lost.
但她只有十二岁  没法独自在外过夜
But she's 12. She can't be out there on her own.
-你们什么都没找到吗  -我知道你很难接受
- You didn't find anything? - I know this is hard.
但我希望你不要自乱阵脚
But I'm asking you not to panic.
我们知道她就在里面
We know she was out there.
我们找了很久
And we tracked her for a while.
我们得有计划地追踪
We have to make this an organized effort.
达里尔对丛林最熟悉
Daryl knows the woods better than anybody.
我把这件事交给他全权负责
I've asked him to oversee this.
那是血吗
Is that blood?
-我们击毙了一个行尸  -有行尸  我的老天
- We took down a walker. - Walker? Oh my god.
他没有碰到索菲亚
There was no sign it was ever anywhere near Sophia.
你怎么知道
How can you know that?
我们把那玩意剖开了
We cut the son of a bitch open,
已经确认过了
made sure.
天啊
Oh god.
你一开始就不应该把她丢在那
How could you just leave her out there to begin with?
你怎么可以离开她
How could you just leave her?
有两个行尸在追我们
Those two walkers were on us.
我得引开它们
I had to draw them off.
这样她才最安全
It was her best chance.
他真的别无选择  卡萝尔
Sounds like he didn't have a choice, Carol.
她要怎么才能自己找回来
How was she supposed to find her way back on her own?
她还是个孩子  她还是个孩子
She's just a child. She's just a child.
当时我真的别无选择  我只能这么做
It was my only option. The only choice I could make.
大家都相信你
I'm sure nobody doubts that.
我的小宝贝一个人在丛林里
My little girl got left in the woods.
大家每人拿一件武器
Everybody takes a weapon.
这不是我们需要的武器
These aren't the kind of weapons we need.
-枪呢  -我们讨论过这个问题了
- What about the guns? - We've been over that.
我  达里尔和瑞克拿枪
Daryl, Rick and I are carrying.
防止某人一听到风吹草动就狂放子弹
We can't have people popping off rounds every time a tree rustles.
风吹草动可吓不倒我
It's not the trees I'm worried about.
假如有人在不恰当的时机开枪
Say somebody fires at the wrong moment,
而那群畜生又恰巧经过
a herd happens to be passing by.
那我们就全部玩儿完了
See, then it's game over for all of us.
所以你就别想着拿枪了
So you need to get over it.
我的计划是沿河而上走五英里
The idea is to take the creek up about five miles,
然后掉头从河对岸再找回来
turn around and come back down the other side.
她很可能就在河边
Chances are she'll be by the creek.
那是她唯一熟悉的地方
It's her only landmark.
保持安静  提高警觉
Stay quiet and stay sharp.
彼此保持距离
Keep space between you
但不要离开大家的视线
but always stay within sight of each other.
大家收拾东西
Everybody assemble your packs.
戴尔
Dale.
你继续修车
Keep on those repairs.
我们得让这辆房车随时待命
We've got to get this R.V. ready to move.
我们可不会无故在这多待一分钟
We won't stay here a minute longer than we have to.
祝你们好运
Good luck out there.
把索菲亚找回来
Bring Sophia back.
帮我们照顾一下卡尔
Keep an eye on Carl while we're gone.
我要和你们一起去
I'm going with you.
你们需要人手  对吧
You need people, right?
这样才能搜寻更多的地方
To cover as much ground as possible.
你决定吧  坏人不能总让我当
Your call. I can't always be the bad guy.
所有人都能照看他
Well, he has all of you to look after him.
他应该会很安全
I'd say he's in good hands.
好吧  好吧
Okay. Okay.
跟大家一样  千万不要脱离我们的视线
But always within our sight, no exceptions.
安德莉亚  我求你了  不要逼我
Andrea, I'm begging you. Don't put me in this position.
拿不到枪  我是不会去的
I'm not going out there without my gun.
我也求你了
I'll even say please.
我这么做是为了你好
I'm doing this for you.
不  戴尔  你是为了自己
No, Dale, you're doing it for you.
别再这样了  你觉得我会怎么做
You need to stop. What do you think's gonna happen?
你一把枪还给我
I'm gonna stick it in my mouth
我就会把它伸进嘴里  饮弹自尽吗
and pull the trigger the moment you hand it to me?
我知道你在生我的气
I know you're angry at me.
我明白你的意思
That much is clear.
但如果我当时不那么做的话
But if I hadn't done what I did,
你已经死了
you'd be dead now.
詹纳给了我们选择的机会  我选择留下
Jenner gave us an option. I chose to stay.
你选择自杀
You chose suicide.
那跟你有什么关系  你根本就不了解我
So what's that to you? You barely know me.
我知道艾米的死让你伤心欲绝
I know Amy's death devastated you.
别扯上她
keep her out of this.
这跟艾米没关系  这是我们之间的事
This is not about Amy. This is about us.
如果我觉得没有活下去的意义
And if I decided that I had nothing left to live for,
你他妈有什么资格阻止我
who the hell are you to tell me otherwise?
逼着我放弃自己的选择
To force my hand like that?
-我救了你  -不  戴尔
- I saved your life. - No, Dale.
是我救了你  是你逼我的
I saved yours. You forced that on me.
我不想让你为了我而送命
I didn't want your blood on my hands
那是我离开那座大楼的唯一理由
and that is the only reason I left that building.
你以为会怎样  你以为我会幡然顿悟
What did you expect? What, I'd have some kind of epiphany?
想要坚定地活下去吗
Some life-affirming catharsis?
也许会心存感激
Maybe just a little gratitude.
感激
Gratitude?
我想在爆炸中死去
I wanted to die my way,
而不是被那些流着口水的怪物撕碎
not torn apart by drooling freaks.
那才是我的选择
That was my choice.
你剥夺了我选择的权利  戴尔
You took that away from me, Dale.
-但是...  -你觉得很了解我吗
- But-- - But you know better?
自从我妹妹死了之后
All I wanted after my sister died was to get out
我一心只想从这无尽的噩梦中解脱出来
of this endless horrific nightmare we live every day.
我没有伤害到其他人
I wasn't hurting anyone else.
你剥夺了我选择的权利  戴尔
You took my choice away, Dale.
你还期待我态度好点?
And you expect gratitude?
我不知道要说什么了
I don't know what to say.
我不是你女儿
I'm not your little girl.
不是你老婆  肯定也不是你的负担
I'm not your wife. And I am sure as hell not your problem.
这就是我要说的
That's all there is to say.
沙恩  看
Shane, look.
老爸说我可以拿着它  老妈说只要我
Dad said I could carry it and mom said as long as I was--
小点声  我们在找索菲亚
Keep it down. We're looking for sophia.
注意力放在找人上
You need to focus on the task.
-跟上  -跟着呢
- Got to keep up. - I am.
-没事吧  -我觉得沙恩讨厌我
- You okay? - I think shane's mad at me.
-我做错事了吗  -没
- Did I do something wrong? - No.
真的没有  宝贝  我保证
No, honey, I promise you.
他只是  只是担心索菲亚  仅此而已
He's just-- he's worried about Sophia, that's all.
走  她可能在里面
Come on. She could be in there.
里面也可能有其他东西
Could be a whole bunch of things in there.
卡萝尔
Carol.
轻声叫
Call out softly.
如果她在里面  让她第一个听到你的声音
If she's in there, yours is the first voice she should hear.
索菲亚  宝贝
Sophia, sweetie,
你在里面吗
Are you in there?
索菲亚  我是妈妈
Sophia, it's mommy.
索菲亚  我们都在这儿  宝贝
Sophia. We're all here, baby.
我是妈妈
It's mommy.
达里尔
Daryl?
不是她
It ain't her.
-谁在里面  -无名氏
- What's in there? - Some guy.
像詹纳说的那样  选择退出了
Did what Jenner said. Opted out.
他是这么说的吧
Ain't that what he called it?
哪个方向
What direction?
我想是那边  我肯定
I think that way. I'm pretty sure.
见鬼  在这里很难辨别
Damn, it's hard to tell out here.
我们都听到了  索菲亚肯定也听到了
If we heard them, maybe sophia did too.
有人在敲钟  也许是在召集什么人
Someone's ringing those bells, maybe calling others.
或是表明他们已经找到了她
Or signaling they found her.
也许是她自己敲的  快走
She could be ringing them herself. Come on
你不去修引擎吗
Ain't you supposed to be fixing that radiator?
要是他们带着索菲亚回来
What if they come back with Sophia
瑞克想继续前进怎么办
And Rick wants to move on right away?
-昨天我就修好了  -什么
- I had it fixed yesterday. - What?
那又磨又搓是为什么
What was all that rubbing and sanding for then?
-是你胡说的吗  -可以这么说
- That's just bullshit? - Yeah, that's one word.
也可以说是演哑剧
Another word would be pantomime--
只是为了现一下
Just for show.
别告诉别人
No one else needs to know that.
哑剧
Pantomime.
要是其他人知道车修好了
If the others know we're mobile,
他们又会组织起来继续走
They'll want to mobilize and move on.
那么你觉得他们找不到索菲亚  是吗
So you don't think they're gonna find sophia, that it?
我只是做最坏的打算
I'm just guarding against the worst.
早晚  要是找不到她
Sooner or later, if she's not found,
大家又会算来算去
People will start doing math.
我只想避开那些过多的争锋相对
I want to hold off the needs-of-the-many-
还有一些争吵
versus-the-needs-of-the-few arguments
越远越好
as long as I can.
明哲保身嘛
That is one tricky hose, huh?
正是
Very.
不对劲  没有尖塔也没有钟
That can't be it. Got no steeple, no bells.
瑞克
Rick.
索菲亚
Sophia!
耶稣  你在聆ste听祷告吗
Yo, J.C., you taking requests?
我告诉你  不是这座教堂
I'm telling you, it's the wrong church.
它没有尖塔  瑞克
It's got no steeple, Rick.
这儿没有尖塔
There's no steeple.
是个电子钟  定时的
A timer. It's on a timer.
我要进去待会儿
I'm gonna go back in for a bit.
你真的要离开吗
Are you really leaving?
你不觉得这对大家都好吗
Don't you think it's best for all of us?
没错  什么使你做的决定
I think it is. What made you decide?
我打退堂鼓了  只想在这里做个好人  洛莉
Gotta back away. Just trying to be the good guy here, Lori,
即使你无法理解  这不是刻意的
Even if you don't see it. None of this was intended.
我希望你能明白
I hope you know that.
无关紧要了  我都已经说了
Well, don't matter. As long as I said it.
你就这么凭空消失  你连瑞克都不告诉一声
You're just gonna disappear? You're not even gonna tell Rick?
他只会试着阻止我  这正合你意
He'd only try to stop me. That's on you.
你告诉他你想怎么样  要么啥也别说
You tell him what you want. Or tell him nothing at all.
你是他老婆
You're his wife.
那卡尔呢  我们把他牵扯进来了
And Carl? We dragged him into this.
-我爱卡尔  -他觉得你讨厌他
- I love Carl. - He thinks you hate him.
我是在试着保持点距离
I'm trying to put some distance.
我想让事情变得容易点
I'm trying to make this easier.
可这样对我们谁都不容易  尤其是我
This ain't easy on any of us, least of all me.
我才是失去你的那个人
I'm the one who loses you.
神父  原谅我
Father, forgive me.
我不配得到您的怜悯
I don't deserve your mercy.
我曾祈祷安全离开亚特兰大而您应允了
I prayed for safe passage from Atlanta and you provided.
我曾祈祷爱德会因为打我
I prayed for Ed to be punished
因为用他内心深处萌生的邪恶想法
for laying his hands on me
看他的亲生女儿
and for looking at his own daughter
而受到惩罚
with whatever sickness was growing in his soul.
我祈祷您能阻止那一切
I prayed you'd put a stop to it,
让我有机会好好地抚养她
give me a chance to raise her right,
帮助她不要重蹈我的覆辙
help her not make my mistakes.
她害怕极了
She's so fearful.
她还太小了
She's so young in her way.
她还有很多路要走
She hasn't had a chance.
祈祷爱德死是我罪恶深重
Praying for Ed's death was a sin.
求求你  不要让我受到如此的惩罚
Please, don't let this be my punishment.
护她平安
Let her be safe,
平安的活着
alive and safe.
拜托了  上帝
Please, lord.
我任由你惩治
Punish me however you want,
但是请保佑她
but show mercy on her.
我要和你一起走
I'm coming with you.
我不知道你到底在说什么
I don't know what the hell you're talking about.
我不是傻子  我也没聋
I'm not stupid and I'm certainly not deaf.
-我不知道有什么故事  -没有故事
- Look, I don't know the story. - There is no story.
那好  我不管
Fine, I don't care.
别拿忽悠别人那招来应付我
Don't confuse me with someone who does.
我现在只关心如何离开这里
Look, all I care about is getting out of here
走得越远越好  和你一样
As far away as I can, like you.
然后我们一起在夕阳下远航吗
We're gonna sail off into the sunset together?
手牵着手吗
We gonna hold hands?
我不是想和你在一起  沙恩
I'm not asking you to go steady, Shane.
我想让你把我带走
I'm asking for a ride,
一个另寻他处重新开始的机会
A chance to start over somewhere else.
你最近观察过这个队伍吗
You observe this group lately?
我有  我发现两个人不属于这
I have. I see two people who don't belong.
就是我们
We're the odd men out.
我们把彼此隔的太远
Between the two of us, we make a great third wheel.
即使这样又如何  逃走吗
So what? Say we do, we just run off.
我又凭什么要帮你这个累赘呢
What's in it for me except for the extra ass I got to cover?
有机会为别人做点事
The chance to do something for someone else.
-好的  -换位思考一下
- Yeah. - And a door that swings both ways.
给我把枪  我也会保护你
Put a gun in my hand, I'll cover your ass too.
好好想想吧
Think it over.
我们得走了  伙计
Got to move here, man.
这帮人累坏了
These people are spent.
还有几个小时就要天黑了
There's only so many hours of daylight left.
-回去的路还很长  -我不能停下
- We still got a long way back. - I can't stop yet.
我们还有很多地方没找
We still got a lot of ground to cover,
包括整条小溪的对岸
whole other side of the creek bed.
我们可以在回去的路上找
So we search that on the way back.
她也许会听到钟声
She would have heard those church bells.
也许就在附近
She could be nearby.
-可能的事情太多了  -我不能回去
- She could be a lot of things. - I can't go back.
她被落到这里是我的错
Her being out here is my fault.
这下好了
That's great.
他们让你怀疑自己了
Now they got you doubting yourself, huh?
你呢  你怀疑我吗
What about you? You doubt me?
我们每个人都犯过错
Hey, we can assign all kinds of blame.
找到她对我们意义重大
This means something, finding her.
天呐
Oh man.
我们需要奇迹发生  决不能放弃
It would be the miracle we need. We can't give up.
你们顺着河边往回找
Y'all gonna follow the creek bed back,
达里尔  你带队
Okay? Daryl, you're in charge.
我和瑞克负责断后
Me and Rick, we're just gonna hang back,
进行一个小时左右的搜索
Search this area another hour or so just to be thorough.
这样我们就分开了  确定吗
You're splitting us up. You sure?
确定  我们会赶上的
Yeah, we'll catch up to you.
我也想留下
I want to stay too.
我是她的朋友
I'm her friend.
-多加小心  -好的
- Just be careful, okay? - I will.
你什么时候长大了
When did you start growing up?
我很快就来
I'll be along soon enough.
拿着它
Here, take this.
还记得怎么用吗
Remember how to use it?
我不会拿走你的枪  让你赤手空拳的
I'm not taking your gun and leaving you unarmed.
我还有一把  拿着吧
Here, got a spare. Take it.
-等我一会儿  -好的
- Give me a minute? - Yeah.
拜托
Come on.
我不明白你这个眼神是什么意思
I don't know if you're looking at me with what?
悲伤
Sadness?
轻蔑
Scorn?
怜悯
Pity?
还是爱?
Love?
也许只是漠不关心
Maybe it's just indifference.
我想你已经知道我不是什么虔诚的信徒
I guess you already know I'm not much of a believer.
我只是把信念放在别的地方了
I guess I just chose to put my faith elsewhere.
大部分放在家庭
My family, mostly.
朋友
My friends.
和工作上
My job.
问题是  我们
The thing is, we--
我需要点东西帮我们前行
I could use a little something to help keep us going.
一点
Some kind of...
肯定
Acknowledgement.
一些我做的事是正确的迹象
Some indication I'm doing the right thing.
你不知道有多难
You don't know how hard that is to know.
也许你知道
Well, maybe you do.
听着  我不需要所有的答案
Hey look, I don't need all the answers.
只想要一点动力  一个暗示
Just a little nudge. A sign.
什么暗示都行
Any sign will do.
-得到你想要的了?  -我想我会自己找到
- Get what you needed? - guess I'll find out.
这就完了?
So this is it?
这就是整个计划吗
This the whole plan?
这计划是要把队伍
I guess the plan is to whittle us down
消减的越来越小吧
Into smaller and smaller groups
随身携带刀和尖木棒
Carrying knives and pointy sticks.
我看到你的枪了
I see you have a gun.
怎么  你想要这枪么
Why, you want it?
来  拿去
Here, take it.
我受够你看我的眼神了
I'm sick of the looks you're giving me.
你们所有人的眼神
All of you.
亲爱的  我不能想像出你正经历的痛苦
Honey, I can't imagine what you're going through.
而且我愿意做任何事去平复它
And I would do anything to stop it.
但你必须停止责怪瑞克
But you have got to stop blaming Rick.
每次你看他时都表露出来
It is in your face every time you look at him.
索菲亚跑走时他没有犹豫  对么
When Sophia ran he didn't hesitate, did he?
一秒都没有
Not for a second.
我不知道谁
I don't know that any of
还能像他那样追着她去
us would have gone after her the way he did
或是像他做那么艰难的决定
Or made the hard decisions that he had to make
谁能做的不同
Or that anybody could have done it any differently.
谁能
Anybody?
你们依靠他还责怪他的不完美
Y'all look to him and then you blame him when he's not perfect.
如果你们认为没有他也照走  恕不挽留
If you think you can do this without him, go right ahead.
没人拦着你们
Nobody is stopping you.
我们该继续走了
We should keep moving.
沙恩
Shane.
不  不要
Oh no. No.
不  不  不
No no no no!